MULLENS e s i g n

EDUCATION:

UI Design Immersion and Front-End Development for Designers

CareerFoundry online tech school program completed in March 2024

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design

Eastern Illinois University Charleston, IL graduated Cum laude in 2004

SKILLS & TOOLS:

- Marketing Collateral, Packaging and Promotional Design: Adobe, Illustrator and In-Design
- UI Design: Figma, Adobe XD
- Website Management: Shopify, Wordpress, Wix
- Front-End Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery
- Photography Editing: Adobe Photoshop, Lightroom, PixIr
- Video Editing: Adobe Premiere Rush, Instagram Reels
- Animation: CSS Animation, Adobe After Effects
- Social Media: Meta Suite
- Social Media Design: Canva, Adobe Xpress
- Email Marketing: Constant Contact, MailChimp
- UX Surveys & A/B Testing: SurveyMonkey, Google Forms, UsabilityHub
- Office Docs: Microsoft Word, & Excel, Google Docs & Sheets

Mary Beth Mullens GRAPHIC DESIGNER, UX/UI DESIGNER

PROFILE:

Level-headed leader and team-player with two decades of experience in graphic design, UX/UI design and marketing. Transforms ideas into compelling, user-friendly creations for print and online realms. Her blend of technical knowledge, artistic skill, and detail-oriented research make her an indelible asset to any company or organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

UX/UI Designer

CareerFoundry - online technology program - 2023-2024

Deep dive into the daily practice and mindset of a professional UX/UI designer.

- Implemented basic principles of User Experience (UX) such as conducting user research, creating user personas and drawing user flows.
- Studied User Interface (UI) design theory, principles, patterns & accessibility techniques.
- Developed mood boards, style guides, wireframes & mockups in Figma and Adobe XD.
- Explored advanced UI skills, such as prototyping animations and interactivity.
- Researched and designed extensive UX/UI for a campground booking website.
- Followed iOS and Android guidelines to refresh native mobile app for CHIRP Radio.
- Redesigned the logo and wireframes for ViaEurasia, a historic walking trail app.
- · Created a brand guide and UI mock-ups for a money-saving website.
- · Designed the UI for a vintage resale mobile app.
- Mocked up preliminary wireframes for a note-taking app pitch presentation.
- Curated every project into an informative case study.
- Exported design assets in appropriate formats for handoff to web developers.
- Gained hands-on knowledge on how to build a website from scratch with HTML, CSS and jQuery, to collaborate with developers and coordinate cross-team projects.

Marketing Manager

Marigold Clothing - Indianapolis, IN upscale boutique - 2014-2024

Responsible for promotions across all channels to increase customer satisfaction & revenue.

- Refreshed branding icons and designed brand guide manual.
- · Developed original website in Wordpress; Launched e-commerce site on Shopify.
- · Maintained website functionality, aesthetics, product photos and blog posts.
- Took photos of merch and models with Google Pixel camera and professional lighting.
- Expertly edited photography with Google Photos, Adobe Lightroom and Photoshop.
- Managed Meta social media accounts with engaging graphics and content.
- Filmed and edited videos for Facebook, Instagram Reels and YouTube channel.
- · Created effective weekly marketing emails in Constant Contact.
- Analyzed email performance & maintained a healthy contact list.
- Designed monthly postcards, ads, signage and packaging with Adobe Illustrator.
- · Planned and advertised promotional events for boutique.
- Set up store displays with visual appeal according to brand standards.
- · Provided training to staff on product knowledge, branding and company policy.
- · Motivated and inspired staff to achieve sales goals.

VOLUNTEER WORK & FREELANCE DESIGN:

- · Branding and social media assets for Love, Broad Ripple association
- · Branding and marketing design for **GRIN2B Foundation**
- · Branding and web design for Chad Thompson Home Sales
- · Logo design for TearDrop Pictures
- · Logo design for HSE Utilities
- · Logo design for Union Brewing
- · Marketing & email newsletters for Broad Ripple Village Association
- · Marketing for Green Broad Ripple environmental non-profit

AWARDS & SHOWS:

reCYCLE pARTS Show

2015

Jury Selected: Poster Design

Primary Colours Art vs. Art

2011, 2012 & 2013

Audience Selected: Top 16 paintings

Eastern Illinois University

2004

Faculty Selected: Outstanding Achievement in Graphic Design

CONTACT:



mbmullens@gmail.com







www.marybethmullens.com

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED...

Graphic Designer and Marketer

Broad Ripple Kiwanis Club - Indianapolis, IN non-profit - 2021-2024

Freelance design and marketing for local Kiwanis organization.

- Designed logos and branding for each of their primary fundraisers (Beer & Chocolate Tasting and Pumpkin Smash for STEAM Cash).
- · Set up headers and event pages on their website.
- Developed posters, flyers, signs, large-scale banners and yard signs for events.
- · Crafted a new t-shirt design every year for sale at their Fall Pumpkin event.
- · Designed informational brochure for sponsor and donor solicitation.
- Set up successful online auction on BetterWorld fundraising platform.
- Promoted events on Broad Ripple Kiwanis' Facebook page.
- Took eye-catching photos during the events for future marketing.
- Organized database of event photography in DropBox.

Senior Graphic Designer

The Bentcil Co. - Indianapolis, IN promotional products manufacturer - 2007-2014

- · Created marketing collateral for promotional product co.
- Wrote & proofread marketing copy.
- · Designed and laid out annual Bentcil catalogs in InDesign.
- · Maintained website using Joomla CMS & HTML.
- · Prepared digital graphics in Photoshop.
- · Took photos of product with a Nikon Digital SLR camera, light boxes and professional lighting. Edited photos in Photoshop.
- · Responsible for all art on products sold to Disney & Universal Studios parks.
- · Designed logos for various product lines within the company.
- Mocked up virtual samples for product orders using Photoshop.

Graphic Designer

Fundex Games - Indianapolis, IN toy & game developer - 2005-2007

- · Balanced workload of designing game packaging and marketing collateral.
- · Created packaging for retailers using their corporate brand guidelines.
- · Carried out designs from concept to pre-press to production.
- · Wrote copy and drew illustrations for game instructions.
- Designed and laid out Fundex catalogs in InDesign.
- · Took photos of product with a Nikon Digital SLR camera, light boxes and professional lighting. Edited photos in Photoshop.

Design Intern

Tampico Beverages - Chicago, IL juice manufacturer - 2004

- · Designed new packaging for beverages and cleaned up existing designs.
- · Created marketing collateral & point-of-purchase signs.
- Set up a brand guideline in QuarkXpress.